WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
Oh, Mr Barrow, you're back.
I'm afraid you've missed luncheon,
but you're in time to help upstairs.
~ Maybe there's something left.
~ Don't bother. I'm not hungry.
~ Charming as ever (!)
~ How's your father doing?
Oh, much better, as it happens. In
fact, he's quite well again.
~ That's good news.
~ Yes. It is.
You remember we're meeting Mr Wavell
at three? Pip's Corner.
Yes, but I don't see the point in
it, since I'm not going to agree.
He's driven all the way from Leeds.
I had a letter from your father.
He says he's in London for a visit.
Shrimpie's in England?
Have you made any plans to see him?
Not yet. He wonders if you might let
him stay here.
Of course, whenever he wants.
~ Is Susan with him?
~ No.
Their time's up soon and she
couldn't face another voyage.
Where will they send him, do you
think? After Bombay.
How are your Russians getting on?
Oh, it's so sad.
They talk about the old days -
dances at the Winter Palace, picnics
on the banks of the Neva -
but there are holes in their shoes,
and they've got no money for food.
This is where Tom says it serves them
right.
Well, I don't approve of how things
were managed in Russia,
but I'm still sorry for people who
have to make a new life in a foreign
land.
Honestly, Papa, every time you
challenge Tom, you sound much more
unreasonable than he is.
Do I?
How's your old beau managing, Mama?
Prince Thingummyjig.
He is not my old beau.
Your father would have called out
any man who said such a thing.
Even so, I do hope you see him
again. Poor old boy.
You don't know anything about it.
How far would the houses stretch?
Well, the whole field, really.
But why can't they be built in a
row, like the other streets?
They'd sell more quickly as separate
dwellings, and we'd get a percentage
of the sales.
So, we're paid once, and in return
the field is lost,
the village is spoiled and Mr Wavell
moves on in search of his next
victim.
Why didn't you tell them we were
coming here today?
~ Oh... ~ They'll find out as soon as
Rose gets home.
I didn't want to be a 'topic' for
the rest of luncheon.
But what are we here for?
Well, something's been troubling me.
Oh, why on earth didn't we get a
taxi from the station?
We must be mad.
Well, we'll get a taxi home - that's
for sure.
It's saying it's in the crypt.
Oh, Isobel, I didn't think it would
be like this.
No, neither did I.
Aunt Violet? Mrs Crawley?
You never said you were coming.
We wanted to surprise you.
Well, you've succeeded.
Ah, there he is.
I must be the last person you
expected to see.
No. I thought you would come.
I've brought my cousin, Mrs Crawley.
Do you remember Rostov?
Count Rostov, I think.
Thank you. Yes. Please, ladies.
Please.
I'm sorry I didn't say very much...
Thank you... at Downton.
But I was... I was so surprised.
You haven't changed. I have.
It's true.
Then, you were the young and
beautiful Countess of Grantham,
turning eyes in a ballroom or out in
your carriage.
Now you are the great lady -
imperious, magnificent.
But these are two sides of the same
coin.
Your life has not much altered in
half a century.
It doesn't seem so to me.
Whereas the handsome and powerful
Prince Kuragin,
with his thousands of acres and his
golden palaces...
That man does not exist. Not any
more.
Ah, Mr Molesley. I've put out some
silver to be cleaned.
I'd be grateful if you could see to
it.
~ Very good, Mr Carson.
~ I was looking for Mr Barrow.
~ He's gone out.
~ Precisely.
But then I thought: No.
This is down to Mr Molesley.
After all, he is the First Footman.
Oh...
I have thought a good deal about
what you said the other day,
when I asked after the Princess.
That I don't know how or where she
is?
It's true.
We were arrested together,
and when I came out of prison, I
heard she'd been exiled a year
earlier.
~ There must be someone in authority
who - ~ Who?
The Soviet Ambassador?
Do you think he cares where Princess
Irina Kuragin is presently lodged?
Well, what about the Foreign Office?
Do they help the losing side in any
revolution? No.
You mustn't give up hope.
When you go through a storm like
ours,
you give up hope quite early on in
the proceedings.
I agree. Hope is a tease, designed
to prevent us accepting reality.
Oh, you only say that to sound
clever.
I know.
You should try it.
I want to call on the blacksmith.
I'll see you back at the house.
Mrs Patmore?
Oh, good afternoon, m'lord. M'lady.
I wish I knew what that was about.
And why the funny look when I asked
after Shrimpie at luncheon?
I suspect he's come to tell Rose
they're getting a divorce.
~ Are you serious?
~ I'm afraid so.
He's hinted at it in his letters,
apparently,
and I gather things have not been
improving.
That's the end of his career.
Well, the Marlboroughs have survived
divorce.
Well, the Marlboroughs are very
rich. Shrimpie hasn't got a bean.
People will drop them like hot
potatoes.
Will we drop Shrimpie?
Susan's your cousin, not him.
No, I won't take sides, whatever
Susan wants.
Would you give me a hand with these?
~ When are you leaving? ~ Lady Mary
wants to get the eight o'clock.
She's going to a dress show with
Lady Rosamund in the afternoon.
~ I'll miss you.
~ So I should hope.
Are you all right? I hope you
haven't let the sergeant worry you.
No, he doesn't worry me.
I just wish we could all forget
about Mr Green.
Why did you want me to go with you
today?
Oh, it was just in case things
turned mawkish.
I prevent Lord Merton saying
anything to embarrass you -
I wanted the same protection myself.
I presume you and Prince Kuragin
were once... attracted to each other.
'Attracted to each other'?
Is that what you call it?
As it happens, he asked me to run
away with him.
~ But you didn't go. ~ No, Lord Grantham
gave me a frame by Faberge,
with two pictures of the children in
it, and I saw sense.
Lord Grantham sounds rather more
subtle than I'd realised.
Well, like all Englishmen of his
type,
he hid his qualities beneath a thick
blanket of convention,
so I didn't see who he really was at
first.
It was lucky you found out in time.
If it was in time.
I forget.
Daisy! Will you put those bally
books away and come and help?
And where are the pastry casings?
~ I'll make them now.
~ You should have made them before!
~ What is all that? ~ I'm studying the
Glorious Revolution of 1688.
Well, there'll be a glorious
revolution down here, if you don't
watch it!
Did you hear that in there?
I mean, mathematics is one thing.
She's studying to be a revolutionary
now!
I hope there's no cooking going on
up in your room.
~ I should find out what he's up to.
~ I'm sure it's nothing.
Lord Merton?
Oh! I er... Well, that is...
You're here.
~ Well, hadn't you better come in?
~ Thank you.
Well, how can I help?
I nearly flunked it,
but I've put it off so many times,
and as I was sitting all alone at
luncheon today, I just thought:
'No. I'm jolly well going over there
to say it.'
I do hope this won't be something
you'll regret.
You may regret it. I won't.
Very well. I'm listening.
I really should go down on one knee,
but I fear I'd never get up again.
I'm sure you realise by now - I'm
asking for your hand in marriage.
Dear Lord Merton, you see -
Please. Please.
I want to be quite clear.
I'm not speaking out of loneliness
or with a view to my comfort.
~ I'm sure -
~ No, you're not.
When men of my age marry, that's
usually the reason.
But my proposal is a romantic one.
I state freely and proudly, Isobel,
that I have fallen in love with you.
And I want to spend what remains of
my life in your company.
I believe I could make you happy.
At any rate, I... I should very much
like the chance to try.
Well, goodness, Lord Merton...
I freely admit you have taken me by
surprise.
Not with your proposal, but with
your... talk of love.
I mean it.
And before you refuse me...
.. I'd like to ask you to leave it on
the table, so to speak.
Say nothing for the time being.
Just think about it.
I'm not sure it would change my
answer,
but after such eloquence,
to refuse your request would seem
ungenerous.
I will think about it.
Well...
Now I think I'll take my leave.
I suspect ordinary conversation
would be difficult after that.
What do you mean, that man Bricker
is coming back? Why?
'That man Bricker'? What has he done
to deserve such a welcome?
Hasn't he seen what he came to see?
He wants to investigate a possible
link between our picture and a later
work by della Francesca.
Shrimpie is coming this week.
Well, then, he and Mr Bricker will
get to know each other, won't they?
Edith, darling, why so glum?
I'm not glum, am I?
How's your prodigy child?
I haven't seen her for a while.
I was getting rather under their
feet, so I thought I'd give them a
rest.
I knew that would happen.
Why don't you leave it for a few
months?
~ A few months?
~ I should.
Then they'll be pleased to see you
when you do go back.
Any thoughts on Pip's Corner?
I'd love to understand the merits of
the argument.
You want us to do it, don't you?
Well, it's capital with no outlay.
We have to consider it.
Consider it, yes. But it's complex.
Do we really want to start breaking
bits off the estate and selling them
piecemeal?
You wanted to sell land when Matthew
died.
And I was wrong. I didn't see how
many owners would chip away at their
land
until there was nothing viable left.
Anyway, we can talk about it
tomorrow.
Not me.
I'm going up to London first thing.
Aunt Rosamund's taking me to a dress
show.
It's good to know you've got your
priorities straight.
Hello? Who's in there?
Please, let me know who's in there.
Go away.
Mr Barrow?
Would you like me to fetch a man to
help you?
Mr Barrow...
What man?
There isn't a man in
this house who'd help me.
What's the matter with you?
Just mind your own business!
Now, you're sure there's no big
evening event?
No, and we're only there one night.
~ When are you seeing His Lordship?
~ Friday morning.
Before we catch the train home.
It's right to do it face to face.
But of course I'm dreading it.
~ Daddy!
~ Hello, Sybbie, my love. Kiss.
Thank you, Nanny. Morning, George.
Morning, Donk.
Morning, Sybbie. Morning, George.
Do we think Lady Mary made the
train? She was cutting it fine.
Mr Stark saw them both on board.
Carson, may I ask you something?
Is Mrs Patmore quite happy?
I'm afraid there is a particular
matter that has upset her, m'lord.
May I know what it is?
But why make him wait?
You mean I must refuse him now?
Well, you said yourself the whole
idea was ridiculous.
Yes, but I can only tell you, when
it came to it, he was not...
ridiculous.
You surprise me.
One kind word and your judgment
takes flight.
Surely Prince Kuragin has reminded
you what one kind word can do.
He's asked me to think about it.
And I will think about it.
It was Michael's office on the
telephone - there's been a
development.
Apparently, there's a trial going on
in Munich.
Of the leader of a group of thugs
there.
I've read about this. They wear
brown shirts and go around bullying
people.
The leader tried to start a
revolution.
That's it. It was absurd.
Maybe. But I'm afraid we're going to
see a lot more of this sort of thing.
We pushed Germany too hard with our
demands after the war.
It seems it was this gang that got
into a fight with Michael.
I can easily believe it. They're a
horrid bunch, from the sound of it.
Yes, but we might be close to
finding out what happened to him.
That's why his office telephoned?
It will be very hard for you, my
darling,
but I promise it's better to know the
truth
than to live in a cloud of mystery
and despair.
But as long as I don't know for
sure, then, in a way, I'm keeping
him alive.
I hate to let go of that.
Can you keep this to yourself, Papa?
Until we're told for certain.
I don't want to put up with Mary's
pity any longer than I have to.
She will pity you, and God knows, so
do I.
I'm fearfully late.
~ Where are my gloves?
~ Don't worry.
It will all be unpacked before you
get back.
You're a dream. I must run.
Oh, wait a minute.
Could you post this?
Or give it to Mead if he hasn't
emptied the box in the hall.
I never said where to meet me, and
Kensington Gardens would be nice and
neutral.
I thought about dining with him
tonight,
but midday seemed more appropriate
for bad news.
Very good, m'lady.
And how is Edith getting on?
~ Actually, she's rather gloomy at the
moment. ~ Do we know why?
She's taken an interest in a child
of one of the tenants,
and now the parents are sick of her.
And why this child in particular?
I don't know.
She took a fancy to it.
Now she seems to have overplayed her
hand.
Golly. That'd be useful.
So, tell me more about this farmer
and his little girl.
~ How did you know it was a girl?
~ Well, you must have said.
He looks after the pigs.
Oh, yummy.
Good heavens. There's Charles Blake.
What's he doing here?
Excuse me. Is this right for Lord
Gillingham?
That doorway. First floor.
Thank you.
~ Hello.
~ Pleased to meet you.
Nice to see you.
Are you shopping for your trousseau?
Ha-ha.
Oh, I think you know Lady Mary
Crawley. Miss Lane Fox.
Oops.
I've suddenly remembered the
significance.
Try not to be an ass, Charles.
Well, we don't know each other,
exactly.
But we certainly know OF each other.
Don't we?
~ It's not often you meet the woman
you were jilted for. ~ Well, I -
Don't worry. I wouldn't want a man
who preferred someone else.
~ You're quite over him, then?
~ Absolutely.
Now I must go.
I'm meeting Ralph Kerr later.
He's very tetchy if he's kept
waiting.
~ I thought you knew each other.
~ No.
And I must say, she wasn't at all
what I imagined.
What was that?
I don't know.
Someone meeker and more virtuous.
~ I don't think Mabel's very meek.
~ No. Obviously not.
~ How long are you in London?
~ I go home tomorrow.
I'll see Tony in the morning and
then catch the train.
~ Why? What are you doing tonight?
~ Nothing.
~ Then why not have dinner with me?
~ Don't you have plans?
None that I want to honour.
I'll come for you at eight.
Nowhere too swanky.
I haven't brought the right clothes.
~ I'll do them! ~ Mrs Patmore, His
Lordship is asking for you.
Come up to the library, please.
Oh, my heaven! What, now? Oh, Lord!
You look fine. Give me your apron.
Ah, Mr Molesley. Just the man.
Can you cast your eye over the
dining table?
I won't have time before dinner, and
you're the First Footman.
~ I was just going to -
~ While you're up there,
check the bedrooms for Lord
Flintshire and Mr Bricker.
I haven't got a moment and, as Mr
Carson says, you are the First
Footman.
Right. I'm ready.
~ Go on, then, Mr Molesley.
~ It doesn't seem quite fair.
You wanted to be First Footman.
What did you think?
That you'd spend all day with your
feet up?
I thought I'd pop in and see how
Marigold's getting on.
I'm afraid I'm just taking her up
for a rest, m'lady.
They've been playing outside and
she's tired.
~ Does she have to go up right away?
~ I think so, yes, m'lady.
M'lady?
The... the trouble is, Margie thinks
you're unsettling the child.
There are laws that govern the whole
business of war memorials.
So Mr Carson's told me, m'lord.
I appreciate how distressing this is
for you and your family.
Do you, m'lord?
Because I'm not sure Mr Carson does.
Carson is as sorry about it as I am.
Aren't you, Carson?
I'm sorry that Mrs Patmore should be
distressed, m'lord.
But you're not sorry Archie's name's
to be left off the memorial.
He volunteered.
He didn't wait to be called up.
He went to the Front to fight, and
as for his so-called cowardice...
that were like a wound in battle, a
wound to his brain,
so he didn't know what he was doing.
He were a good and decent lad.
~ Of course he was. ~ But doesn't that
make him a casualty of war, m'lord?
Same as our William or any of them.
He could have stayed here, safe and
well, until they came for him.
But instead, he chose to
fight for his country.
It may surprise you to learn, Mrs
Patmore, but I agree with you,
even though I can do nothing about
it.
It's not helpful, but I do.
No, it is helpful.
It helps to think that decent folk
can see our Archie was a victim.
Even if Mr Carson can't.
Thank you, Carson.
When does Shrimpie get here?
And your ghastly art dealer.
They're on the same train and the
car's meeting them, so they'll have
time to change.
And he isn't a dealer. He's a
historian.
Is he, indeed? Lawks a-mercy.
I wish I knew why he was coming.
~ He wants to discuss the painting.
~ With you?
Yes. Is that so shocking?
I'd better get on.
Oh, Mr Molesley. I've not been told
whether Lord Flintshire and Mr
Bricker will be bringing valets.
Could you make it your business
to see they're properly attended?
Well, I've got a lot on my plate, Mr
Carson.
I am sorry, Mr Molesley,
but you are -
Yes, I know. I know. I'm the First
Footman.
So, you're happy?
Well, I'm not delirious, but who is?
I have a pretty good life.
Well, I'm glad.
I was never the type to die of a
broken heart, you know.
I'm sorry if that offends you.
On the contrary. I only hope Tony
feels the same.
Goodness. I wasn't expecting that.
I wish I could work you out.
I wish I could work me out.
~ When will you tell him?
~ Tomorrow.
I'm meeting him at noon.
By the Peter Pan statue in
Kensington Gardens.
Won't that make him dream of happy
families?
Well, it's too late to change it
now.
What's he done wrong?
Nothing.
I'm very fond of him.
I'll always be fond of him.
I want him to be the godfather of my
children. Just not their father.
~ How will he take it?
~ Not as well as you.
Well, you've got a way to soften the
blow. If you want to.
~ I don't see how.
~ Don't you?
~ You seem a little subdued tonight.
~ Do I, Granny?
How strange. I wonder why.
I know it sounds hard, but you must
learn to leave things behind.
I suppose you mean I'm to leave
Michael behind now,
as you've already made it quite
clear I'm to leave the baby behind.
I would never suggest anything that
is not in your interest.
In my interest? Or the family's?
To me, they are the same.
And that is where we differ.
I've been thinking about your
missing person.
Oh, I don't want to be a nuisance,
but aren't there departments devoted
to finding people who are lost?
Alas, not at my command.
And the Russians who were driven out
have spread to the four corners of
the earth.
Who is this woman?
An old friend of yours?
No, she's the wife of an old friend.
Oh, just see what you can do,
Shrimpie.
Aunt Violet - if I can still call
you Aunt Violet -
I ought to warn you about something.
~ I can guess what it is.
~ You won't approve.
No. I don't.
You may even feel the need to take
sides. Susan is your niece.
Well, I think you're making a
serious mistake, but you may rest
easy on that score.
I never take sides in a broken
marriage.
Why is that?
Because, however much the couple may
strive to be honest,
no-one is ever in possession of the
facts.
Are you in a hurry to leave
tomorrow?
Not at all. In fact, at the risk of
being a burden,
I thought I might stay another
night.
~ When are you off tomorrow?
~ He's staying for a couple of days.
Is he? Well, I hope we've got enough
here to amuse you.
~ Come into the library.
~ Excuse me.
Why not invite Miss Bunting to
dinner tomorrow night?
Mary will be back - we'll be quite a
party. Edith, persuade him.
I don't think Papa would think it a
very good idea.
~ What's this? ~ I wanted Tom to invite
Miss Bunting to dinner tomorrow,
but Edith says Robert won't allow
it.
Nonsense. Of course you must bring
her, if you like. I insist.
~ So, you've enjoyed Bombay for the
most part? ~ Oh, yes.
It's a wonderful city, the gateway
to the glories of the East.
I felt very privileged.
I gather things have not improved
with Susan.
No.
The times I've blessed you and Cora
for keeping Rose out of it.
What happens now?
Divorce, I'm afraid.
I can't see any other way.
But my dear chap, is it worth it?
Why can't you just live apart?
If you'd ever been as unhappy as I
am, you'd know why not.
Has Molesley gone to bed?
Yes. Why?
Mrs Patmore needs two more chafing
dishes first thing tomorrow.
You can tell him in the morning.
You're not so pally now, are you?
Why are you still up?
I just want to get this finished.
Your father was never ill, was he?
I'm sorry?
Are you the one who's ill? Is that
it? Is that why you went away?
~ What's it to do with you?
~ I'm right, aren't I?
You're ill, and you went away to be
treated,
and now you're trying to carry on
with the treatment yourself.
Well, it has nothing to do with you,
so just leave me alone.
Robert asked why we couldn't stay
together, for the look of the thing.
I hope you see that we can't.
But Daddy, where are you going to
live?
Your mother will keep Upper Brook
Street.
I'm not sure where I'm going to go
yet, but I'll find something.
Oh, can I live with you?
To be honest, I think you should
stay here for a while.
The next part could be quite
unpleasant.
I'm learning from it, though.
I don't care how eligible some chap
may be - I'm not going to be
bullied.
~ Fighting talk.
~ I mean it.
You all think that now I'm
officially 'out', it's time to find
my man.
But I'm only going to marry if I'm
totally, absolutely in love.
Of course.
When I find him, will you promise to
be on my side?
Promise you won't try to force me
into a 'suitable' marriage, like you
were forced.
In other words, you're asking for a
blank cheque.
Yes.
That's just what I want.
Oh, my dearest one.
On the subject of marriage, I have
no right to give advice,
let alone orders.
'You must make haste to reach
Dieppe,
where you are to seek out a Mr
Avebury.
He will arrange for you to be taken
aboard a packet and conveyed to
safety,
but do not delay, if you hold your
mother dear.'
Poor woman. I know how she felt.
'As for your collection, Mr Avebury
will do what he can,
but I'd rather every canvas or
carving were tossed in the sea
to your being one extra hour in that
unhappy country.'
I'm glad he didn't take her advice.
He did not.
He brought crates and crates over,
then went back after the Reign of
Terror to buy more.
And you have preserved them safely
in this beautiful place.
I'm glad you think it's beautiful.
I think everything about Downton is
beautiful, including its mistress.
~ You mustn't say such things.
~ I have to, or I'll burst.
What's burst?
I was just saying that...
being allowed to touch a painting
like this will make me burst.
~ It's wonderful to show it to someone
so appreciative. ~ Yes.
No-one could say you're not
appreciative, Mr Bricker.
~ I can't be hearing this correctly.
~ I'm afraid you are.
So, you sleep with a man because he
wants to marry you,
but now you change your mind.
It's insane!
I'm sorry if you think so.
Well, I won't let it happen.
I love you and you love me.
At least, you told me so in
Liverpool.
I know, and I thought I meant it.
~ Well, what's changed?
~ I can't explain, exactly.
But something has. That's all.
Am I a bad lover? Is that what
you're trying to tell me?
Don't be silly. It's not that at
all.
It's just, I feel I've sort of...
woken up out of a dream.
How flattering (!) We go to
bed together and you wake up!
I'm just not sure we have enough in
common, to make a go of things.
Well, I refuse to accept it.
I refuse to believe that a woman
like you, a lady,
could give herself to a man without
first being certain that he was the
one.
~ So, what are you saying? ~ This is
something we've got to get through.
And we will. We will get through
this together.
Mr Molesley. You wanted to see me?
Only to say
that I'm not sure I should be called
the First Footman, after all, Mr
Carson.
~ Are you not?
~ No.
Well, it's not like the old days, is
it?
I mean, the duties of the First
Footman are shared between a lot of
people now, aren't they?
~ Are they?
~ Well, they should be...
because I've got the duties of the
Second and Third Footman to deal
with.
So, you don't feel you need the
precedence that the title 'First
Footman' confers?
Er... well, not really, no.
Very well.
I'll see what I can do.
~ I wasn't sure you'd want to come.
~ Nonsense.
I'm flattered to be asked.
I didn't think I would be again.
Not after last time.
Try to be nice to him tonight.
I will be, if he's nice to me.
I know you don't like him, or any of
them, much,
but you forget one thing -
they are good to me, in their way.
And I love them.
I don't want you to hate them.
Just to realise that you're more
than a retainer.
I can't bear for you to waste your
life propping up a system that's
dying.
Well, it won't die before dinner.
Someone's dropped this in the
passage. The London Magazine.
~ Does it belong to any of you?
~ Mr Barrow was reading it earlier.
~ Would you give it to him when he
comes down, Miss Baxter? ~ Of course.
Where did you get this?
Have you been in my room?
Of course not. You dropped it in the
passage. Mrs Hughes found it.
Mrs Hughes found it, but Miss Baxter
read it.
I'm sorry for what you've gone
through, if what I think is correct.
Don't you pity me.
Don't you dare pity me.
Did you bring the photographs of
della Francesca's Nativity?
I certainly did. We can compare them
to the painting tomorrow.
It would be so lovely if it does
turn out to be a study for it.
Yes. It would be absolutely lovely.
Mr Bricker, one more word and I will
ask you to sit somewhere else!
He flatters her. He keeps asking her
opinion on everything.
Well, don't you ever ask her
opinion?
Of course I do. Sometimes.
~ Did you have a good time in London?
~ Quite good.
I set myself rather a difficult
task,
and it's always a relief when it's
done, isn't it?
~ How are your lessons going?
~ What's this?
Miss Bunting is giving instruction
to Mrs Patmore's undercook.
Oh, yes. I heard about that.
~ You sound as if you don't approve.
~ I approve.
As long as you're not making... her
unsettled.
You don't know her name, do you?
~ Sarah, please.
~ Of course he does.
Daisy.
~ Well, he knows it now.
~ I knew it before.
And it sounds as if you're upsetting
her and Mrs Patmore.
I think you should drop this.
Why don't you send for her?
Bring Daisy in and ask her yourself.
~ I'm sure she's too busy. ~ Not too busy
to answer a summons from you.
We don't want to embarrass her.
Carson?
This is the busiest time of their
day, m'lord. Maybe it would be
better -
No. Fetch her.
And ask Mrs Patmore to come up, as
well.
Very good, m'lord.
Your father may regret this.
~ I wondered if you wanted a hand.
~ Almost done.
You could put the cases away, if
you've a mind.
~ Did you enjoy yourself?
~ We weren't there long enough.
I went to deliver a letter to Lord
Gillingham in Albany.
Oh, yes?
Then I walked into Piccadilly.
His Lordship's lucky to live there.
~ Do you recall Mr Green saying that?
~ Saying what?
Jimmy heard where he lived and
called him a lucky tyke.
He wasn't very lucky in the end,
though, was he?
No. He wasn't lucky in the end.
Right. I'll take these up to the
luggage room.
~ Is something wrong with the dinner,
m'lord? ~ Not at all.
We apologise, Mrs Patmore,
for interfering with your duties in
this strange and inconsiderate way.
Mrs Patmore, Carson tells me
you feel Daisy's lessons have
disturbed the peace of the kitchen.
~ Did you say that?
~ I don't know what I said.
I was upset
about that other business.
I wondered if it were true. Daisy?
Well, I'm sorry if I've made trouble
downstairs.
Well, you haven't. Not really.
But I must say this, m'lord.
Miss Bunting here has opened my eyes
to a world of knowledge I knew
nothing of.
Maybe I'll stay a cook all my life,
but I have choices now, interests,
facts at my fingertips.
And I'd never have had any of that
if she hadn't come here to teach me.
Brava. Well said.
~ Quite a testimonial.
~ May we go, m'lord?
We've still got the pudding and the
savouries.
Of course. Thank you.
Obviously, the lessons have proved
successful.
I'm pleased to hear it.
Are you, Lord Grantham?
Oh, for heaven's sake, let it go.
You've proved your point.
Have I, though? All I've proved is
that Lord Grantham
would like us serfs to stay in our
allotted place from cradle to grave.
There is only one thing I
would like...
and that I would like passionately.
It is to see you leave this house
and never come back!
Happy now?
Edith, dear, are you still writing
that very interesting column?
Yes, Granny.
Oh, you must show me some of them.
What is the latest one about?
What are they all about?
The way the world is changing.
What's happening? What's all the
commotion?
He just left the room.
Oh, I don't mean to interrupt.
No, no. We were just discussing the
Battle of Little Bighorn.
The Battle of Little Minx, more
like.
To speak to His Lordship in that
manner! In his own house.
It's true, then? I thought Mr Barrow
might be exaggerating.
It seems he wasn't, for once.
Mr Branson must be horrified to have
brought her here.
I don't know.
I like him, but sometimes I think
we've forgotten the Mr Branson that
was down here with us,
spouting Keir Hardie between every
mouthful.
They've made him one of them in a
way, but it's not who he really is.
Then it makes me wonder whether
Downton is the place for him.
A question I'm sure he's asked
himself many times.
~ I can't stand that woman.
~ No great surprise there.
I suppose you think I made a fool of
myself.
~ What does it matter? ~ I don't see
that you were much better.
Flirting and twinkling with that
ghastly travelling salesman.
Go to sleep, and when you wake up,
make sure you get out of bed on the
right side.
Good night, Tom.
And cheer up.
You gave Granny a wonderful evening.
Well, what a to-do!
It seems to me your friend Miss
Bunting is out to make trouble.
She's brought me to life, Mrs
Patmore.
All the same, she wouldn't win a
popularity contest upstairs.
Would you like to write a letter to
the War Office?
~ Oh, don't be daft.
~ I mean it.
If you think Archie's been badly
treated, you must protest.
I wouldn't know how to write a
letter like that.
~ I can write it for you.
~ It won't do any good.
His Lordship says there are rules in
place. He wouldn't lie.
No, but if you protest and then,
over the years, more and more others
protest,
then they might change their blessed
rules.
This is your learning, isn't it?
That's what you're trying
to show me - you're not afraid.
No, I'm not.
Well, go on, then.
We'll do it tomorrow.
~ How can we help you this time?
~ It's an odd business.
Since all this started, they've kept
a plain-clothes man on watch
at Lord Gillingham's set in Albany,
and now I'm told that Mrs Bates was
seen there, loitering outside.
Well, I know why that would be.
Lady Mary must have wanted to see
Lord Gillingham while she was in
London.
No doubt, Anna was sent with a
message to arrange a meeting.
I knew you'd have something sensible
to say. Sergeant?
Well, it seems likely.
But from there, Mrs Bates walked
into Piccadilly,
to the spot where Mr Green died.
There's no possibility she might
have a grudge against him,
that Mr Bates might share?
Not that I'm aware.
As I recall, she rather liked him.
~ Mrs Hughes?
~ Yes, she liked him. So she said.
They may want to question her, but
before they do, they want me to
check one thing.
She was definitely here on the day
of his death? Here at Downton?
~ I believe so.
~ Surely, you can't think that Mrs -
I'm not paid to think, Mrs Hughes.
Just to record the facts.
~ Hong Kong? ~ A lot of the Tsarist
sympathisers ended up there.
~ How did they survive?
~ As servants and taxi drivers.
Milliners and prostitutes. Anything
they could lay their hand to.
I will not suggest to which of those
callings the Princess Kuragin was
most suited.
If you dislike her so much, why are
you going to all this trouble?
~ Because I owe it to her.
~ Why?
By the way, Susan has written to
Annabel
to say that she's furious that
you've all taken me in.
Oh, dear Susan has been in a rage
since she was playing with her dolls.
I am proof against her tantrums.
I would rephrase that if you want to
stay neutral.
I won't take sides - it's true.
But I don't think I could ever be
described as 'neutral'.
Have you apologised to Tom?
I never knew anyone who could
provoke me into saying so many things
I don't believe.
But I am sorry, Tom.
Please forgive me.
~ She knows how to goad you.
~ With the precision of a surgeon.
~ Why do you go on with her?
~ Since Sybil died,
I've forgotten what it's like to be
with someone who feels about things
as I do.
That's why. Or that's been why.
To me, it's as if you'd joined us
and now you're backing away.
What are we doing here?
I want to explain why I think we
should turn down Wavell's offer.
I know. We are only the caretakers
of Downton.
But Papa, some things have to
change.
True. But we mustn't destroy what
we're trying to protect.
Wavell would wreck this lovely place
for ever, with his ugly, cheap
houses.
~ But you can't block all development.
~ I won't.
I intend to expand, but without
spoiling.
I'm going to make a plan and find a
solid builder
who can fit in to the village and not
ruin it.
~ That may be hard to achieve.
~ It may be harder
than cashing Wavell's cheque, but
does that mean we shouldn't try?
No.
We will build.
We'll even make money for the
estate.
But we won't destroy what people
love about this place.
Do you think that's wrong?
No. It's not wrong.
That's all I'm asking.
Have any of you heard of someone
called Atticus Aldridge?
I should think carefully before you
say one more word.
I'm afraid you've read somewhere
that rudeness in old age is amusing.
~ Margie feels you want the child to
be your plaything.
~ How can she say that?
~ And you liked Mr Green?
~ Yes, I did. Very much.
You despise the family, but I think
you forget - my child is one of
them.